yeah it's because bug Crut doesn't know
that I can hack Hardware I need to hit
them up and be like hey way me submits
one bug a year on bug Crut Hardware God
no
[Music]
[Applause]
yo yo yo we're rolling yo yo how's it
going pretty good dude this uh this past
couple weeks has been kind of crazy but
we're getting ready to kick off a live
hacking event again so it's not going to
slow down I don't think oh dude nonstop
it's not it's like one thing to the next
thing to the next thing yeah yeah well
at least you got a you got a week off
last week from the Pod yes a little bit
barely yeah you had crazy stuff going on
though so that's That's How It Gos yeah
yeah yeah all right um yeah let's check
out the news stuff for the day um first
first up on the docket was naham khon uh
who are sponsoring this episode so thank
you naham Khan um just wanted to give
them a shout out and say I'm going to be
speaking there on the Saturday um
Saturday slot at 12:20 and I'm going to
be giving a presentation on uh PCI DSS
uh which is essentially payment card
stuff um and how pretty much every
single website that we've seen is
vulnerable to some sort of trickery in
this area due to the way that the uh DSS
structures uh recommended structure is
so there's going to be some really
really awesome content in that that
will'll drop so definitely don't miss
that on on Saturday at 12m PST yeah dude
I'm really looking forward to that um I
know that naham always has amazing
people on for his his his con and just
for his show in general and all the all
the content that he makes but uh yeah
it's super awesome I'm I'm super stoked
to see what you talk about there I think
I think the in particular I think is one
of the one of the best structured ones
for bug bounty hunters because you know
Ben just has such a good Network in the
bug Bounty Hunter you know field that he
can put together a bunch of people that
really know what they're talking about
and have differ expertise to share I was
looking at the lineup and there's a
bunch of um you know eclectic hacking
Styles and you know you've got people
from like influencers like stul all the
way down to you know uh people like
Douglas day that just really get in
their requests every single time so uh
it's really it's really cool to see the
the whole the whole gamut being run
there yeah yeah it should be awesome Yep
um yeah oh man man the next the next
item on the news list makes me so sad
man I just you
know on Twitter you know you see Gareth
Hayes talk about JavaScript stuff all
the time and he's one of those people
that like you can just feel the passion
when he talks about JavaScript like he
just freaking loves JavaScript and uh
and he tweeted out earlier this week and
I I threw it on the list that his
favorite xss Vector is going to stop
stop working I think is it like November
when they're they're going to depreciate
it uh yeah I didn't catch the exact date
but from 119 November
2023 um they're going to depreciate uh
data URLs inside of the use element in
svgs yeah yeah so for those who aren't
aware this is basically like one of the
really common ways that you would pop an
xss within an SVG not just like SVG on
error or on load or whatever but within
the SVG element itself you can include
stuff like um you know well with this
use element um you can use different
different things I think it's meant to
take a bunch of different data types
yeah it uses a data URL here and and
kind of uses that within the within the
SVG itself um but it seems like they
they want to have that that piece that
uh that data element removed from the
SVG uh use element and that would result
I guess you potentially you could still
load it externally um but then you've
got CSP stuff that you're going to run
into so it's it's a double-edged sword
there yeah yeah I know there are a
couple other um vectors and looking at
the web AC the web Security Academy on
Port swigger um there there's these ones
that use animate inside of SVG oh yeah
and not all of them some of them do use
that use element but not all of them do
so I'm wondering if that will still be a
valid attack Factory yeah I mean as long
as as long as the it's not because the
use element is still staying it's it's
just that the data URL inside of the use
element um is is kind of going away uh
and I think I'm looking at the reason
for removal and it looks like it's
largely you know because the sort of
same origin issue that that's going on
there um so sad to see that go but
really cool vector and i' always love to
see uh Gareth Hayes talking about xss
stuff I I have he's one of one of the
people that I do have notifications
turned on for tweet notifications turned
on for because it's just like every
single time it's super high quality
research and I just I really appreciate
that yeah yeah yeah I me he's always
yeah I mean he's just like he's such a
JavaScript like fanatic you know it's
like all he does it's like his main
focus so he he's one of those people
that has so much insight about the
Nuance about what's going on yeah so any
anything that you can do to like consume
gareth's gareth's knowledge is something
I would recommend yeah and I I love that
little I love that I love that he wrote
a little book too you know like I I feel
like that's something that people that
specialize in the industry it's it's
really handy because the book is not
long it's not very hard to consume you
know but it it outlines all of this cool
you know [__] that he has in his brain
that otherwise we wouldn't have access
to and so I definitely I definitely
endorse that method not only just for
knowledge sharing reasons but also just
for it's a great thing to do when you're
a specialist you know take take the you
know however long it takes do a little
brain dump on this topic that you're
just a super expert at and put it out
there and now you've got a product that
you can you know you're getting
reoccurring income from and you're also
sharing that knowledge with a large
community large community excuse me so
that's that's really I really respect
that yeah for sure uh and we've talked
about this as well in the past like any
type of the it's not it doesn't have to
be like groundbreaking research right
but like any of that knowledge sharing
type content is really amazing for
building out the community and just like
helping other hackers learn and get
better and help secure everything as a
whole quirks sometimes it ends up being
one of these things where where like
eventually the browsers will come and
they'll like patch something that
shouldn't behave that way or whatever
but like yeah okay yeah you know that
sucks for us as hackers but it's good
for security as a whole and I think like
that Insight is is valuable regardless
yeah dude it makes me think of that of
that I man did we cover it on the Pod or
did it just make it into the news list
but it it makes me remember this one at
a live time at a live hacking event
there's this guy bit K that showed me um
this way that you can exfiltrate data
via VIA fetch um and what what you do is
you you know you get it cached and then
you say Hey you force fetch to use cash
and it was like at the time it was just
like oh this is like totally amazing
because you could get a cookie you could
get a cookie to you know uh get the data
and then it would cash the response and
then you could send the fetch request
without the cookie with cashing you know
pull from the cash set to mandatory and
then it would pull the results back and
it was just just like man this is such a
genius method and so that's really smart
mean it's sad because you know those
those methods get deleted you know as
soon as they become popular but if
you're lucky enough to have met you know
a great researcher at like a live
hacking event or at networking you know
sometimes you can pick up these little
tidbits that will you know really help
you pop some crazy bugs during
engagements so yeah yeah for sure um did
you hear about this this move it uh the
move it vulnerability oh my gosh yeah
it's hard to it's hard to have not not
have heard of that man Twitter is kind
of blowing up about it yeah yeah so I I
was reading about this and uh it's this
like file like Transfer app right and
yeah yeah that was my understanding I
hadn't actually heard of this before
like of what of move it until the
vulnerability they were saying it's all
over the place but I actually hadn't
seen it very much so I wonder you know
actually how much net presence it does
have yeah yeah it was super interesting
so um I wasn't sure they said that
Huntress uh is that who who owns it or
is that the people who found that's I
think that's um John Hammond did some
work with them and I think he uh he sort
of did this whole I guess sort of I
don't know if this is like an incident
response yeah they call it rapid
response um to this sort of
vulnerability and I thought this was
really cool because um you know even and
I I I also linked that in the click
click the Twitter Link in the doc right
but below that Joel like I I love to see
this sort of thing John is like out
there at 4 a.m tweeting like oh man I
can't figure out like oh is this it and
he's like putting screenshots of code
and I just you know I read through that
whole thread and I was like man this is
why you know he rocks this is why PE you
know if you can come into this with this
much passion where you're up at like
4:00 a.m. like you know really just
trying to grind out this this PC because
what what he was trying to do was
reverse the PC you know reverse the flow
from um I guess it looked like in the
beginning all he had was a packet cap or
like a like a log of the various um
endpoints that they hit so you know if
you click that that um image at the top
of the Tweet it's like you know it hit
move it is api.dll and then it hits a
couple other things and so he's trying
to like follow that flow and figure out
how they they ended up popping this this
shell um so yeah it's it's amazing to
see you know when people are that into
it and that like enthralled and then
they look up it's like 4 a.m and you're
like ah what the heck
yeah yeah no that's awesome yeah it
actually looks like he works he's a
researcher at Huntress so yeah yeah so
super super interesting it sounds like
they basically yeah like they got a
packet capture or something like that um
and so they started digging into it and
trying to figure out like how it was
working and and the whole chain and I
don't want to like spoil all of this cuz
I think it's worth reading yeah they
they don't drop the full exploit either
which is you know for me a little bit
disappointing but also you know totally
reasonable I I think surely it's already
somebody's already figured it out right
like yeah yeah yeah so it's a really
awesome um I feel like this would have
fit perfectly with our source code
analysis episodes that we just did um
but yeah this is one of those cases
where you just do the Deep dive you keep
digging digging going through rabbit
holes trying to figure out like how does
this code work how does this code work
what is this code doing and eventually
you you get to the root of it and uh and
it's it's really awesome um it's a super
interesting case study for sure terms of
like how something like this would work
out in the wild um and uh I think that
there's definitely some like learnings
that you could pull away from like an
organizational standpoint or How Could
You Secure your org to protect against
this like in the future like what kinds
of rules and stuff would you want to
keep an eye out for are there certain
traffic patterns that you should be like
looking out for that might have popped
up if you were exploited by this that
kind of stuff yeah he he adds like some
yarro rules and like some um indicators
of compromise to the to the right up
which is great too um and yeah just like
you said you know about going down
rabbit holes if you go to John Hammond's
Twitter right now and you know on on
June 3D I so that's the next day you
know he's like oh we finally got it and
he's like P.S it doesn't have anything
to do with the crazy [__] that I was
spewing at 4
a.m. so it's like I just I feel that man
and uh yeah it's it's cool to see you
know for those of you that are always
thinking like ah man I'm not sure am I
going down the right path you know how
do I how do I know
um look at John here you know one of the
most skilled guys out there on the arena
you know he does education in you know
cyber security stuff all the time shout
out to his YouTube channel excellent
amazing YouTube channel um and even he
goes down these rabbit holes and ends up
you know ah this is the wrong thing so
it definitely happens it's a part of the
process and at the end of the day if you
keep on being persistent um just like
John you'll you'll end up popping the
full bug for sure yeah for sure um I
think as well um it's really
interesting like I I feel like I've been
in that scenario so many times where
I've I've spent like eight hours or like
more just like looking at one thing and
I'm so invested that I don't want to
step out of it yeah but like do you have
any what do you do when you're in that
scenario well it's it's funny you
mention that because um I'm gonna
actually just pull it up on my email
right now there's somebody messaged um
this week uh into info@ criticalthinking
podcast. and he said this is the
question you said when you were hunting
and you're doing recon and getting a
feel for the app you have something
interesting that you are poking at how
do you know you are on to something
promising do you have any tips for
knowing when it is time to cut bait and
move on how to know when the PO uh the
potential for success is there or
whether it's not worth the effort and I
was like yeah that's that's the rub
right you know to just bring it back to
the Shakespearean eye that's the rub you
know whether it is nobler to continue to
pursue down your rabbit hole or to you
know I forget the rest of the quote but
it's MC Beth so I yeah I was not I
English was my least
fa they they made us do like a like a
presentation of that and I was the guy
reading that so I should remember it but
you know whether is nobler to continue
to hack or whether is noer to not
continue to hack um is the question and
yeah it's really it's really hard to
know man um and I think at some point
you know you kind of get to a point
where you're like all right I've looped
on my on my brain so many times like
keep on just coming to the same
conclusion same conclusion same
conclusion and for me it's probably five
or 10 cycles of that you know somewhere
between five and 10 cycles of that
before I'm like man I'm not really sure
I'm going to find anything else at this
at this specific code pathway and that's
when you start working back and I will
add this is one of the things that I
think de um was developed for me a lot
by the ocp um because the ocp has a has
a time limit right you know you've got
24 hours and if you spend too much time
going down a rabbit hole that you can't
you know
that doesn't end up with anything you've
lost a bunch of time so um that is that
is something that pretty much only comes
with experience I think is is knowing
whether when to to cut you know cut your
losses and move on or whether there's
something there um so I would say you
know to the listeners that are wondering
about this question um yeah I'll just
call them CG thanks for the thanks for
the question CG um you know experiment
with it right so you know if you maybe
you'll do one session where you're like
all right anytime I run into a wall I'm
just going to move along right and I
know some people that do that actually
and and you know it works for them and
that's great and I know some people that
you know if they run into a wall 15
times at the same end point they're
still going to keep going at it so you
got to figure out what is right for you
as a hacker and where that limit lies
and and it can be something that's
intuitive uh or it can be something you
know that's set and concrete saying hey
I thought where am I going to go five
times now time to move on check you know
and you you move along so what do you
think about that Joel yeah I think I'm
I'm very similar where it's not like I'm
not an instant kind of pass when it when
it's pushing back a little bit I do like
to push through it a little bit further
just to see like am I missing something
here is there something more to this am
I just doing something like you know
very minor here that is blocking me up
here like sometimes I I'll be like
testing something for a while and I've
just made like a simple error in my
request or something that's like it's
the worst right you spent like an hour
and you're like H I guess this is like
tot and then you're like oh my god I've
been using the wrong the wrong request
this whole time or something like that
like yeah that's where hacking can
really help too right yeah that extra
set of eyes is so useful just having
somebody who's like hey uh that's the
that's the wrong request
like just that the extra little second
brain on your shoulder yeah that that's
super helpful um but I think for me it's
something like it's very similar to like
what you have it's like some it's I have
a specific number but it's a certain
number of times where I run and hit the
Rick wall and I'm like okay I should
probably move on and some of it will
also depend on whether or not I have
other interesting things to be looking
at I feel like that also affects my like
how lenient I am to just move on and go
to the next thing because if something
has been really like pulling at me like
this is something interesting I need to
look at but I need to finish what I'm
looking at right now if I'm not getting
anywhere with what I'm looking at right
now it I'm more likely to go start
looking at that new thing no that that
totally makes sense and I I think I I
have that same mentality but for me I
think it feels a little bit more like a
surrender when I move away from it like
I I think I do have a little bit more of
that fighting Spirit than is good for me
sometimes you know and I've talked about
this publicly on the Pod before how I
used to not really do that at all and I
would just move along and you know that
was those were the days when I was
finding a bunch of like you know idors
and access control stuff because I was
getting a bunch of volume because I was
moving along so quickly as soon as
anything would would you know bump into
my way right and you know if it's a
function of volume you know for those
sort of bugs because it works or it
doesn't work it's not there's no
fiddling normally but um when I started
you know banging my head up against a
wall sometimes when I saw an attack
Vector that's when I started finding
these more serious vules um that are
more deeply embedded in the apps and
started walking away with some bigger
bounties and you know to be perfectly
honest looking at the statistics my
amount
earned hasn't changed that much between
those two strategies I think it's a
little bit higher where I'm at now but
um you know my amount earned does not
actually deviate that much because the
like like we've said it before those ID
doors and those a control issues can be
extremely impactful and if you can get a
bunch of those it really pays off big so
it's it's really up to the individual
hacker yeah so so do you have a
preference between the two in in
hindsight like having done both and
seeing that there's not a huge impact on
the on the earnings would you would you
ever go back to the first one or or no I
mean I I I think my preference is
strongly where I'm at now because it's
more interesting and and it feels more
risky and sometimes it's a little bit
less you know a little bit more
stressful because you're like well if
this doesn't pop then I'm screwed you
know but um but you know I think as I've
developed as a hacker in my Stress
Management and my anxiety management as
well you know over bug Bounty and as
I've become a little bit more
financially stable as well and and you
know realizing hey it's not the end of
the world and I've also just become a
little bit more confident in who I am as
a hacker as well you know in my identity
as a hacker um I I you know definitely
lean a little bit more towards the
ladder now like a let me let me spend a
little extra time let me find some cool
[__] and and um spend a little bit less
time grinding through the the burp
requests um but I definitely recommend
that in the beginning for any beginner
as well because if you can hit a lot of
volume you'll see a lot of you'll see a
lot of HP requests and like we talked
about those reps lead you to be a better
hacker so there's there's definitely you
know you could go either way depending
on which way you want to
grow yeah yeah and I think one of the
other things I recommend is especially
this this happens early on a lot when
you first start hacking you're just
going to be like looking at stuff and
it's going to be hard to find your first
bug and moving on is really difficult
because when you first start you don't
know when you should move on and like
you have like no context in terms of
like what what does that feel like or
like where is the right place to draw
the line and so I'd say like if when you
do decide like to move on don't like
don't think about it too much like don't
let it beat you up because you have to
remember that like all the bug Bounty is
basically trying to beat the odds you're
trying to like find something that is
bad that shouldn't exist and you're
trying to like break the system that is
designed to keep you know customer data
safe for whatever it is and so if you
don't find
anything it doesn't mean that like you
failed right it just means like that app
might be secure and that's good and
that's that's okay and you know it's
time to just move on to the next thing
and find something that feels less
secure so that you can find all the
holes in it you know yeah yeah and you
know we we preach this on the Pod all
the time you know there's a whole team
of people that are dedicated to you not
being able to do your job when you're
doing book bounties so it's a really
it's a really challenging thing but we
believe in you you got it so uh go get
those bounties um and I I will say uh
you know for the more experienced
hackers out there as well don't get set
in your ways don't don't get so tied up
in your approach that you never that you
never experiment because I know I grew a
lot as a hacker as I started Ed um
experimenting away into the more rabbit
holy sort of uh find the weird [__] uh
sort of things rather than the volume of
of requests um so I think there's a lot
of room for growth there as you
experiment with um the various
techniques so yeah 100% nice man well we
that was that was a nice little little
Vibe we deviated a little bit from the
plan but I'm I'm glad we talked about
that because that's those just really
important things yeah for sure um all
right so this is what I had on on on the
plan for today Joel um we did as we
mentioned before we've done uh a good
bit of Hardware hacking lately um with
the live hacking event that uh we last
went to so this is the episode where we
talk a little bit more about that where
we give some details on some of the
techniques that we used and uh kind of
go into
detail um so I mean we could start with
the hardware Recon is that does that
work for you Joel or you got anywhere
else you want to start no let's let's
let's start from the top you know yeah
so um click click that link that's about
that's in under the um the next bullet
point there uh because I wanted to ask
you something specifically about this so
you know if you scroll down um and we'll
link this link this is uh this is
riverloop Securities Hardware uh hacking
right up you know you scroll down and
eventually they're soldering onto test
pins on the back side of an emm emmc
chip right yep um so for those of you
that just that just sounded like garbage
uh emmc is an embedded multi media card
is that right I think uh yes M card yeah
um and and that is sort of like the hard
drive of these iot applications where
they're storing the file system it's the
nonv volatile storage right um and so
one of the reasons we want to get at
that is because it contains the source
code uh in in the actual file system for
the iot device we can be really
insightful to us as hackers um so uh
what I wanted to talk wanted I wanted to
ask you Joel in this sort of Hardware
Recon section is like there are these
test pins on the back of that and we can
use those if we can find these test pins
that correlate to this emmc protocol I
guess we can use those to read from the
emmc chip as well not and we don't even
have to pull the chip right off the
board is that right yes so in some cases
yes some cases no yeah they talk about
it a little bit so typically if you want
to read off off an MMC chip while it's
like in use that's probably not a great
idea um for a couple reasons it it would
be basically like trying to read a hard
drive while it's plugged in and being
used so there are other operations
happening on the drive at the same time
from a different like from the host OS
that hasn't mounted and so it might be
reading and writing at the same time it
might be performing operations it might
have stuff locked like you never know
and there might be like conflicting data
with the controller within the with the
m within the MMC sure that will cause it
to like have problems so
so sometimes that works sometimes it
doesn't but it's really good for at
least at the minimum like looking at
like the buug like what's going on like
is this are these pins the right pins is
this chip functional like am I looking
in the right area all that kind of stuff
but it's potentially possible to use
those test points um to interact with
the chip if we can figure out a way to
have the chip um activated you know with
with power um and not have the CPU you
know hitting that same bus is that is
that right right yeah so like to the
best of my understanding you could
literally just pull up the spec for that
ship read through it see what the
voltage is supposed to be see what the
amperage is supposed to be take out a DC
power supply set it to the right voltage
and amperage connect it to the VCC and
ground
and Power It Up power the power it up
yeah yeah and then okay so that's cool
cuz that that actually gives us a second
a second um sort of route to get or I
guess maybe a third or fourth throughout
depending on how much stuff we get to
cover today but um essentially for me as
a more of a more of a beginner I I feel
like I've kind of got a grip on some of
the hardware hacking stuff now but what
what my playbook kind of looked like was
like okay is there a uart interphase on
this device so you search around you
look for the uard interface and we'll
talk about uard and JTAG on a different
episode that'll be um a hardware hacking
episode too but um and then if if you
can't find those then you just do a a a
chip pole and throw it into to a reader
and then try to pull the operating
system off and that way but there's
actually another method that doesn't
destroy your device because that's the
problem with the chip off method is it
destroys your device and if you can use
if you can you know solder some pins
onto these uh uh onto these sort of test
test pins there or solder some
connectors onto those test pins and hook
that up to a um some sort of device that
can communicate over
emmc then uh and I think in this in this
uh blog that will link in the
description they use a logic aner here
to figure out which um which individual
pin correlates to what part of the emmc
right um then you could potentially get
a a file system read through through
that and it would still come across as
like an SD card to your computer right
yeah so
generally like I like this approach
because it's very like ground up like it
doesn't require you to pull up the the
data sheet or anything like that however
I would say in most cases like 99% of
cases you can literally just take the
chip number Google it pull up the data
sheet and you know exactly what the pin
out is like most of the time yeah most
of the time you you don't need to be
like figuring out which is the clock pin
because they're not changing that stuff
like that comes straight from the
manufacturer of the chip sure um there
are cases that I've seen where uh either
there will be like uh so so typically
there's a DOT on top of a chip and that
dot is in one of the corners and that
references which one is Chip which one
is pin one um and so oh sometimes
they'll put a dot somewhere else or or
they'll put a dot on multiple Corners so
you don't know which which pin is pin
one and so you have to figure it out
yourself that's Savage dude that's so
freaking Savage yeah and I'm not sure
whether or not that's like purposeful or
whether or not that's like just you know
they make a chip that can be used in
multiple configurations so they put it
you know in multiple I don't I don't
know but um I have seen that out out
like I've seen pictures of that on the
wild so um that's just something to be
aware of but if you have a very like
straightforward chip there's like a
single dot on the top uh you can also
just there are easy things you can
verify so for example every Chip is
going to have a voltage and a ground pin
so if you take your multimeter and you
put it on continuity testing uh which
will basically tell whether or not the
signal is going between one probe and
the other probe um typically there's a
way to make it so it beeps and then you
tap the the leads together it goes beep
right so that's continuity testing you
put one lead on the ground pin from your
data sheet you read the data sheet you
go okay this should be the ground pin
and then you either you can go as far
back as you want you could go all the
way to the power connector and one of
those pins should be power one of them
should be ground and you can test and
see is there continuity between these
pins yes or no and you can do the same
thing for VCC and that's also how you
can test these the test pads and see is
this pad pointing to this pin or this
pin on the chip um and then that's a
pretty easy way to determine whether or
not it's using a standard pin out or not
nice nice so I mean I guess we can do
that to a certain degree with with a
multimeter right and and and you know
with the continuity testing like you
were talking about but when it gets to
something like for example in this
article it was talking about the various
pieces of emmc protocol which I'll I'll
kind of uh touch on very lightly for for
the audience that haven't read the the
um the write up yet but essentially
there's three main parts of of the
protocol that you need to identify
there's the there's the clock there's
the CMD which is um the the line that's
used for sending commands and then
there's uh data zero um and that's the
the minimum requirements that you need
to be able to communicate over emmc um
with the actual chip so this is this is
uh we're we're getting much lower than
we normally do here on the Pod because
we mostly talk about you know web and
mobile stuff but this is actually
talking about Hardware level protocol
stuff which I think is really really fun
to dive into um but but you know once we
start trying to identify all those
little pieces that's where we really
need a logic analyzer versus a
multimeter because we have to be able to
actually read the blips in in um power
coming across those those various um
lines is that right yeah yeah so
basically like what what the logic
analyzer is going to be doing is it's
going to be looking at at shifts between
high and low uh where that's basically
like a high voltage or a low voltage
where it's either drawing where it's
pulling it down or it's pushing it up
and
so for example the clock pin that they
identify super easy to identify that
because it runs like a clock right it
goes on off on off on off on off on a
very regular schedule and that's
basically telling the chip like how fast
it should be operating and then data is
for data and CMD is for telling you what
to do um and so you know it's it's
basically a straightforward is that but
logic analyzers will make that so much
easier just because a lot of the stuff
that's built into the software will do
it automatically so in the article they
use a s uh I use uh it's called
a anal L Discovery 2 uh by digilant um
it's pretty good it's cheaper than a s
but uh I think if I were to buy one
again I'd probably go with the S just
because um it's a little bit higher spec
it's a little bit more expensive but the
software is really really good and it's
generally considered one of the
top-of-the-line tools that are out there
um yeah digilant actually did just like
last week announce um the analog
discovery three which is an improvement
to what I have um it has I think faster
polling rates faster measurement rates
it uses USBC instead of micro USB it's
got a couple different things um but uh
but yeah no any any sort of like logic
analyzer is going to be a good
investment if you're doing this type of
Hardware hacking just to identify like
what's what's going on is this pin
youart is this pin J tag is this nothing
like what is it yeah that that yeah
that's a good point I I think I got a
little I get a little excited about this
stuff and I jump right in let me let me
just say you know this is relevant to
you all as bug bounty hunters out there
you know the majority of our audiences
are active you know active bug bounty
hunters because this is a very very
untouched scope normally like if you can
go ahead because one because the tools
are very expensive and you know what we
talk about here on the Pod you invest
the money you get the tools you buy the
premium you know and it opens up a bunch
of scope that pays for itself um and and
a lot of these Hardware programs out
there on hacker one or bug crowd you
know you have to buy the piece of
Hardware yourself and then you're going
to break it and it's going to be
annoying um but if you go through that
um that difficulty if you pay the price
the bounties are much higher so I'm
hoping that we can Inspire some of you
to sort of pivot into the hardware
hacking realm um it's really fascinating
and there are a lot of really good
writeups out there actually on it um and
so and it's not as as hard as you would
think to Pivot into it yeah and I think
one of the things I would recommend if
you or somebody that you know has a
background in electrical engineering
yeah this is a great space to dig
into because like a fundamental
electrical engineering background is so
helpful for just understanding some of
the basic stuff like why are things
behaving the way they are uh how how
would I interface with this if I want to
read data off of this pin do I need to
like have a pull down resistor what is a
pull down resistor right like there are
like so many fundamental electronic
questions that would be so much easier
to answer if you have any sort of
electronics background it doesn't even
have to be like a full like electrical
engineering background if you've done
basic Electronics stuff for many years
which lots of people have yeah like
robotics any of that kind of stuff
working with electronics you're familiar
with like voltages um like how circuit
boards are designed created built all
that kind of stuff like this is a great
area there's not a lot of people who
know this kind of stuff it's a very like
sparse knowledge space within hacking
bounties are good yeah yeah like if you
can pop one of these devices it usually
pays like a significant amount of money
because most of these are owned by like
large conglomerates they have a lot of
money on the line they have a lot of
people with this device in their hands
yeah and there's just a skill set
mismatch too right there's not as many
people that can do Hardware hacking
stuff as there are web because it
requires tools it requires background
knowledge um and so I think I think you
know the competition is is a little bit
less and there's more of a demand you
know supply and demand just sort of
dictates that the bounties would be
higher yeah yeah and I also just wanted
to mention um two things on on what you
just said one this is a great um
reference to uh the conversation that
Corbin and I had last week on the Pod
and we'll link that in the in the
description but um we have a great
conversation about what kind of degree
is best for a hacker to get and this is
you know this conversation we're having
with Joel here is one of the main
reasons why I suggest a computer
engineering or or even maybe even
electrical engineering degree for some
hackers because you get a lot lower
level understanding of things and it's
so much easier to build on top when you
have the bottom bricks right you know
think of it think of it you know
sometimes if you're trying to get an
understanding of things you don't know
what's happening underneath you kind of
got this very shaky understanding you're
very shaky base and then you're trying
to build bricks on top of it but if you
have a solid base then it becomes so
much easier to just boom build up the
wall and and you've got a great
understanding I don't know man my I have
a little bit of self ious about my
analogies because Mar Mariah always like
Justin that analogy doesn't make any
sense but hopefully that one hopefully
that one came through to you guys no no
I I 100% know what you mean like I I get
that same s where especially with
Hardware hacking I'll be honest like
Hardware hacking is that for me as well
because I'll be like working on
something and I'll be so confused as to
why it's not working and a lot of the
time it's just because I've made a
simple mistake due to a lack of
fundamental knowledge or understanding
and it's very hard to find those
problems or answer those like unknown
questions without the knowledge right so
like I think this applies to like
beginner hackers as well it's like how
do you know when to draw the line to
stop hacking and move on how do you know
when you have no experience and no like
knowledge or context like when to draw
that line do you just guess right like
is there any sort of like concrete
identifier and that that is very similar
for like Hardware hacking where it's
like how do you know if like this is
just a fundamental thing that like you
you need to go learn or if this is just
a common problem that even the experts
hit or like what is going on here where
do you draw the line so I wouldn't beat
yourself up too much over it but if you
have that solid fundamental knowledge
that that solid foundation it's going to
make things so much easier yeah and and
I think the the procrastination
education uh piece with Hardware hacking
is a little bit different too because
sometimes you really do need to be like
ah actually I don't know about this very
specific little thing for example we
were Joel and I were working on a on a
project where we needed to read from an
rpmb sort of uh it's not really a read
protected memory block you know on an
EMC chip and uh we we had never even
heard of that so we both had to go and
like read the white paper on that
specific you know piece of technology
and kind of understand what it does at a
lower level to be able to come back and
hack so it there's definitely some some
some different tricks you know in the
hardware Hardware hacking field that
that to get caught up on but if you can
pull it off one you know I I would I
don't think I'll ever forget this moment
in my entire life Joel that first time
we took the chip off of there and I put
it into my computer and I just saw like
15 different partitions like new disc
new disc new disc new disc found I was
like you've got to be kidding it's so
satisfying like I cannot believe I just
pulled I took this device apart I took
the chip out of the device and I put it
into a you know a thing and my computer
just read it like that's nuts so there's
there's lots of really amazing feelings
that kind of come along with uh you know
diving into Hardware hacking and you
know finding your first little Pathway
to getting source code or you know a bug
so yeah dude I'm not gonna lie even
after all that reading on
RPMs dude no one such a stupid protocol
man still like I don't even know like
like I I don't know if I could describe
like what it like what it is how it
works like how it's supposed to be like
if we did anything right there cuz like
when we eventually got on the on the
device while it was running we could
access it but after we had pulled the
chip we couldn't so I I don't know I
it's still very confusing to me but it's
it's a super interesting topic area yeah
it's you know it's replay protected
memory block right so it it replay oh
that's what it is it's replay protected
memory block and and so essentially the
whole point of that is like you
shouldn't be able to write to that block
without um having some some going
through the Authentication Protocol but
there's a bunch of things that say
online that because the spec is a little
fuzzy about whether you can read from
that without having the authentication
key and really if you read the actual
dock the actual spec for the for the
device it shows that the encryption
piece of rpnb is just um an A hmac on
the read side right so you know if you
don't choose to validate that that Mac
then uh you know you can read from it
just fine um and it's mostly I think
designed to um protect against tampering
um at a hardware level level so anyway
it's a cool thing I do I do know a lot
more about it now than I than I did
before um so that's that's cool but you
know I I don't know when that will ever
come in handy again next time I'm doing
like just one of those little brain
brain space fillers exactly exactly okay
so getting back so we we look around on
the board for test pins um see if we can
hook up to those test pins see if we can
figure out some way to get a you know
power up the chip uh via VCC or you know
maybe I think in the art
yeah we'll definitely definitely check
out the article because there's so like
some stuff they mention in here about
glitching with the CPU to like try to
get it to not try to read over that that
um you know read that disc so maybe
there's some cool stuff you can do there
yeah yeah you can definitely do do some
like power glitching and stuff to try
and get the CPU in a weird State um I do
generally like trying to power it with
the onboard power stuff okay uh if I can
so for example if I'm trying to use like
uart or something I definitely want to
have it do it normal I I basically want
the device to think that everything is
normal and that it's getting all the
same you know power delivery and
everything that it would while
functioning normally instead of trying
to rig that myself I probably could but
I don't know if something's going to go
wrong right I don't know if there's
special power requirements that the chip
is doing or that other things on the
board might need and the last thing you
want to do is fry something on the board
accidentally because there's so much
that's like the biggest risk in my
opinion is that you fry something in an
expensive piece of hardware and then you
have to buy another one or call it quits
yeah that those are ni and sometimes
hacker one and I assume bug crowd does
this too but I haven't had that
experience with bug crowd so I don't
know they do okay um yeah it's because
bug Crow doesn't know that I can hack
Hardware I need to hit them up and be
like hey by the way me submits one bug a
year on bug crowd who is Hardware God no
um yeah but you know it's really nice
when the hacker one programs and the bug
crowd programs actually send you the
hardware to test on without you having
to pay for it okay so we've we talked
about the logic analyzer we talked about
a little bit of Recon so let's say for
example we can't get the test pin to
work test pin method um with our sort of
natural power and we can't get it to
power up you know giving it power
directly so we got to go for a chip pole
um
and yeah so there are some there's some
equipment that we need for this um and I
kind of noted some of them down here
Joel you can kind of take a quick look
over that make sure I wasn't missing
anything but uh the essentials are a
heat a heat sort of a heat gun or a heat
hot air station I think is what they're
called and um and that will allow you to
just very send very focused hot air on
the specific chip so you know you strip
down the device you find the emmc chip
um and you can find that by Googling you
know what text is on it and sometimes
it's obvious from the way that it looks
but yeah you know you set that hot air
station up you shoot hot air on it and
then what happens Yeah so basically
for for like the mental image for people
who are just listening a hot air station
is if you've seen a heat gun it's not
like a blow dryer it's like just the
like straight part of a blow of a blow
dryer without the handle and it
basically is just an electric coil that
blows hot air and then it has these
little funnels on the end like you
mentioned that like narrow the hot air
down to like a very you can see it
you're you're pointing at it right for
those on YouTube you can actually see it
on my on my desk behind me but for those
of you on audio listen to Joel sorry
yeah so there's like a little you know
it's like a giant pen kind of thing and
it's wired up to this power supply and
then on the power supply you set what
temperature you want it to run at and
then there's a little nozzle on the end
that controls how large of an air flow
that it's it's pushing hot air out and
then it just has a fan over a heating
element and it just blows hot air okay
and this hot air can go very very hot
like burn yourself easily burn yourself
very very very very hot so this is not
something to like just you know mess
around with obviously be careful with as
you're using these tools um you know
respect respect what it can do it is a
heat gun it creates heat you can get
burned I have got burned yes yeah me as
well yes I uh I had a hot plate that I
was that I was also doing some Dearing
with it I just like stuck my hand on it
by accident I forgot it was on so that
was fun um but yeah so a hot gun a heat
gun a hot air hot air Reflow rework
station it's called up a lot of
different things we'll link some stuff
down in the description for for those
that kind of want a basic setup yeah but
what you need to what all you need to
know is that basically chips generally
speaking have two different forms they
have pins that are like coming off the
side of them that are then soldered down
to the board and then they have these
things called a BGA a ball grid array
and a BGA is essentially little tiny uh
balls of solder that connect underneath
they like it literally sit it sandwiches
on top there's the chip then there's
balls solder and then there's the board
right underneath it and there's contacts
on the board underneath it and it holds
it you know once the solder is not
melted it holds it there essentially
acting as the pins that connects it
between the the the contacts on the
bottom of the the chip and the contacts
on top of the board um and so when we
use a hot
air gun we're essentially heating up
that s those little balls of solder
underneath such that they liquefy enough
and then you pull the chip off and
that's it like that that's basically all
you're doing you're doing what you would
do with a soldering gun or a soldering
iron sorry like you know the hot tip
thing and you know put it on whatever it
smokes and [__] it's all that but it's
just like from a distance right so
you're just doing it with with hot air
yeah yep with hot air yeah and so you
know I guess more more concretely you
know you get the hot hot air station and
you're you're kind of using that pen and
you're going back and forth and back and
forth and um I think the last time we
did an assessment Joel we set it to
about 400° c um but I think the best way
to do it to preserve the safety for the
devices excuse me is to set it at like a
lower level maybe like 250 or so and
then sort of slowly work your way up so
you know you shoot it you know back and
forth back and forth for about a minute
and a half two minutes and then you you
know you try to lift the chip and it's
you're you're not going to be forcing it
it's literally just going to be a lift
like you're going to put the grab your
tweezers that's another thing you need
you're going to grab your tweezers
you're going to grab the trip with the
tweezers and you're going to try to lift
up and if it doesn't come with you don't
force it and then you you know sort of
back off let the chip cool down a little
bit because you don't want to fry it so
maybe wait two or three minutes and then
you know bump up the heat to 275 or 300
or something like that um and then sort
of work your way up um I think the place
we found it was around 400 425 maybe is
is a good spot um and then eventually
you know you do that for
sometimes it's not even 30 seconds
sometimes it's like you know a shorter
amount of time and you'll be able to
just lift the chip right off um and then
you've done a successful pull hopefully
if you didn't rip off any pads yeah so
I'm sure that there are some some like
Hardware people cringing cringing as
they're listening to this being like
400° 425 yeah um so the one one thing
I'll say is most of these hot air guns
are made cheaply
and they do not have the best quality
control and they're not the most
consistent things especially across
Brands and across devices so your
mileage is going to vary probably
greatly from someone else's and you will
just need to do some testing on your own
um like Justin said I would start at a
low temp like start at melting point of
solder so like probably around 200C and
just work your way up if you're you know
you're constantly moving your air gun
you're heating the whole area the the
thing that you mentioned this but you
didn't really explain it you need to be
constantly moving the air gun around the
chip because you need all of the balls
of solder underneath the chip to be
melted at the same time evenly yeah
that's important right and the other
thing is flux oh my God flux is your
best friend yeah so yeah so flux paste
flux all it basically it helps solder
flow this is not really optional I I you
know this is very important yes you need
flux like big time so flux helps solder
flow it helps prevent it from
oxidizing and so essentially what that's
going to do uh solder has surface
tension essentially that's what holds it
in place um when Justin said that the
chip will be very easy to pull off it
it's like a water bug on top of a a
surface of water the chip is basically
magnet it in place because there are
copper contacts underneath it and there
are coer contacts on the top of the Chip
and the balls of solder that are between
it are surface tension to those P those
pieces of copper and it's holding like
if you were to bump the chip it would
snap back basically because the solder
is holding it in place if it's doing
that that means it's ready to lift so
your goal is that you want all this OT
to be liquid enough that you can
basically bump the chip and see it
wiggle and then just lift it there
should be no Force you're you're not
peeling you're not you're not sort of
you know starting at one side and like
sort of lifting it up a little bit no
you're gonna break the chip that way
don't don't do that yeah it's really you
know very lightly and you know maybe not
even with the pointed tip of your
tweezers cuz you don't want to like
scratch it or like you know cause any
damage to the chip you're just kind of
gently pushing against it and if you
like Joel said if you don't see that
sort of um movement then it's not ready
to pull so yeah there's a lot of really
good videos well actually there's not
there's a couple really good videos out
there that are I gon to say I don't
think so yeah yeah uh uh you'll find I
think a lot of these are more like for
repair and they don't care so much about
the Integrity of the chip that they're
pulling off um and that's fine uh as
like a demonstration but just keep that
in mind with temperature right like
generally speaking if you were to read
the spec sheet for these chips these
chips are not designed to be in
environments that are above probably
like 100 degrees Fahrenheit or like you
know 30 degrees Celsius or something
Meanwhile we're heating them up to like
200 400° C
so you know part part of that is that
that's the direct temperature coming out
of the gun but that's not the
temperature that's hitting the Chip And
that's also why we want to move it
around and we want to keep constant flow
so that all that heat isn't targeted
into one specific place it's going to
fry or melt stuff within the chip um so
yeah those tweezers super useful if you
look at any videos online you're going
to see basically lots of flux lots of
moving the heat gun around eventually
you they'll tap it they'll tap it with
like some really fine point tweezers and
they'll see that it it moves and then
they just grab the edges of it and just
lift it up um you know microscopes some
people really like to do it under
microscopes some people like to do it
under like a magnifying glass some
people like to just do with their
eyeballs depending on the size of the
chip you may or may not need to do that
um you know it's really it's really up
to you and your your eyesight I guess
but um I I do it without a microscope
the the other thing is for those of you
watching on YouTube again you can see
over my shoulder this this little device
that Joel uh you know freaking
influenced me into
um it's called what is it called is it
called handy hands that's it yeah and
it's got like these these little sort of
for those of you listening it's sort of
like Doc O style um you know flexible
arms that kind of grip the the CH uh the
actual board and then they have sort of
um a magnifying glass light and they've
got like a little uh clamp there that
you can use to hold the board and it's
it's just got some nice things that make
the whole process go smoother um and so
I would recommend those that made it a
lot easier for me I know when I because
I didn't have that uh when Joel and I
were doing the my first PLL I was
actually trying to uh heat up the chip
on top of a heat sink to keep it flat
and I was and Joel was like dude what
are you doing no stop um and so uh yeah
definitely definitely a good recommend
there um yeah and then any kind of Handy
hands is really good yeah the really
good product I I really like it um and
then so once you pull the chip off you
got to clean it and you got to clean it
better than you think you got to clean
it um just coming from a beginner's
perspective here cuz I was like ah you
know this is probably fine nah you
really want to take the time with
isopropyl alcohol and a Q-tip and you
know gently with some tweezers and you
know you want to put uh I think you Joel
even use like uh the tip of a soldering
um Iron and sort of drag some some flux
or some uh some solder around on it
right yeah yeah so it's called reflowing
and basically you take like you know a
larger than normal blob of solder and
you can just heat it up and and get it
so it's it's like stuck kind of yeah
it's melted but it's it's stuck to the
end of your um soldering iron tip and
then you just want to Glide that ball of
solder over the contacts over the the
copper contacts on the bottom side of
the chip after you removed it and that's
going to one pick up any extra solder
that that is on those pins and it's also
going to uh put a thin layer of solder
back on top of of any ones that don't
have solder on them so it's going to
basically like clean up it's going to
uniform unifor right right right and
then you just you know lift it off and
you should have the your your big baba
solder still on your your your iron and
that's going to help prevent any
contacts from getting bridged any of
that kind of stuff the uh the flux yeah
isopropyl alcohol the higher percentage
the better 99% if you can get it 91 is
probably what you'll find at like a
store or something um but yeah just a
Q-tip uh or a cotton swab or anything
like that um you know just be aware that
can leave like Little Fibers behind yeah
I don't like that yeah so just be aware
of that um you know some Q-tips are less
fibrous than others I guess less hairy
than others so yeah what what I did when
I was doing it was I actually pulled off
a little bit of the hair you know and
kind of made it a little bit less hairy
you know when I first started using the
Q-tip and then you know that sort of got
it to drop less fibers so or maybe even
you could like you know twist it in your
in your hand and try to compact some of
that down so that it doesn't leave as
many fibers on there CU that is a pain
to get off afterwards I think maybe I
used a microfiber cloth or something
like that at one point to try to get
this off yeah something like that so
yeah reflowing it and using isopropyl to
clean any excess uh flux um those are
the two ways that I generally CL clean
the bottom of a chip if you're having a
read problem with a chip and it looks
like visibly like there's no defects in
the chip there's no physical damage all
the contacts look like they're intact it
doesn't look like any of them have been
ripped off or anything like that clean
it again just mhm that's number one I
just say clean it again because we had
that happen both on my side and Justin's
side where a chip wasn't reading
properly in the reader took some more
ISO just cleaned it one more time there
must have been like a thin layer of flux
or something that was you know
interrupting their yeah I don't know but
uh yeah that fixed it so man that last
one that last pull that you did on the
last exercise or on the last you know
thing we were working on like it was I
mean he was holding it up to the you
know to the webcam and it looked like it
just came out of the factory man it was
like clean as could be so that's the
goal it was mint um so that was that was
really cool um and then one of the other
things I just wanted to mention we're
going back you know so well actually
we'll go back after let's let's go ahead
and finish this up so you clean it and
then we're going to go ahead and put it
in a emmc chip reader um there are quite
a few different devices out there um the
only one I have experienced using is not
on my desk right now but it's a it's an
all socket em reader um very easy to use
it has a bunch of uh nice little uh
plastic fittings you can use for
different sizes of emc's it does not we
did run into an issue last time where it
actually didn't have the right plastic
size um to get it to read which was kind
of a pain but um uh we found another way
to do it so that was good um but yeah so
that's one option and then I know people
also use something called a uh T56 um
yeah uh let me pull it up Universal
programmer um and I've had of that so
yeah so I have both of these the BGA so
the all socket BGA emmc reader super
super useful like you mentioned it
basically has different base plates that
um will hold it over the right pin like
the pin readers within the the socket
adapter um the thing to note about that
is one it's quite expensive for like
it's a very targeted tool so it's
designed for I think it's BGA 159
or something 186 or let me let me pull
it up real quick yeah and and when he
says it's very expensive I mean it's
it's in the hundreds range not in the
thousands range because I I'll just
throw it out there like it was $87 but
it's it's just this adapter right $87
plus $8 of shipping um and it's designed
for uh
emmc fbga 153 and 169 Okay so
specifically that's like those are two
different form factors of Chip uh it
might refer to like the number of no it
doesn't it can't be the number of solder
but it's it's it's like it's a specific
form factor of Chip basically and you'll
see like if you're reading the data
sheet that there will be different form
factors for different chips a lot of
them will fall into the same categories
but as just mentioned for example we
pulled a BGA chip that was I think it
was a BGA 153 but it wasn't the right
you know size dimensions it didn't have
the face plate to hold it in the adapter
so you know we couldn't read it very
easily and I had even tried like 3D
printing an adapter to to fit it in
there and it it didn't it didn't really
work that well yeah yeah that was that
was uh that was a little bit of a bummer
so definitely you know if you're going
to buy specialized equipment for a
specific thing you know I think these
all socket emmc readers will cover the
large majority of the ones but you know
you got to know you may run into a
situation and you may want to measure
the size of the chip beforehand in
millimeters and make sure it supports
that form factor um I do want to
say I I said it just a second ago but
you know Joel said they're expensive
there are some things on Amazon that are
selling these things for like two and a
half Grand that is not what we're asking
you to buy do not buy that um there're
there're there're cheaper options I
think it was like yeah $100 or sub $100
so we'll link some of those down in the
description um you know you can find
them on some of them you can find on
Amazon some of them you can find on some
of the other websites um so don't go and
spend like two and a half grand for one
of these things it's ridiculous yeah
yeah for the t-56 that's really good um
for like uh yeah so that's good for like
nand flashes and stuff it has different
use cases generally when I use that
um uh well a nand is just like a basic
like part of a chip it's like a an
electronic like structure but um a nan
flash it's just a different type of
flash like as opposed to an emmc or nand
FL they're different types of flashes
nor flashes um but uh you can buy these
large sets of adapters so I have a huge
box that's full of just like uh every
type of t-p like t-p 48 t-p 56 like
every single you know t-p or soop
adapter that you can think of and then
on the bottom it has these little pins
that they're just you know pin headers
and essentially you clamp it in this t50
and then you plug it into your computer
and you can read it um and it's just you
know it's a different way of mounting it
um generally the all socket one I'm
using for BGA stuff I suppose you
probably could do BGA stuff this way
with the T56 yeah it says it says um if
you here I'll send it to you right now
on Discord if you if you look at the
third item down um it it says supports
BGA 45 63 64 15 153 162 169 221
so I I think you know it definitely has
a wide range of BGA that it's compatible
with yeah yeah so I think the main thing
is you just have to get the right
adapters for it um I'm not I'm honestly
not sure like how this thing works like
every time I've ever used it I just plug
it in and uh it it it either has the
chip in the software or it doesn't and
uh it just like yeah I don't know it's h
it's kind of weird but it's it's pretty
useful yeah so this could be a good one
a good one um to check out and add to
your to your Arsenal as well I think
probably altogether I spent maybe five
or $600 on sort of like a beginner setup
for all of this stuff um when I was
first starting out um so you know
definitely it's not cheap to get into it
but also now I've got the tools that
I'll use in the future as well um so
that's that's pretty helpful yeah yeah
Hardware hacking is one of those things
where you could easily spend a couple
thousand dollars on on tools and still
not have the right thing that you need
um so I would just say do a lot of
research before you buy stuff especially
specifically for your use case so like
what specific chip do you want to use
this tool for is it going to work for
that chip um and don't be surprised if
it doesn't work for other chips um just
that's kind of just the way it is uh if
you can find some of those more generic
tools um sometimes they're more
expensive and they'll require some more
like effort on your side in terms of
like programming or like maybe you'll
have to write something custom to
interface with it but those tools will
let you interface with almost anything
nice yeah that's awesome I I definitely
value that flexibility a little bit
because it's it's nothing there's
nothing worse than like you sit down on
a weekend and you're ready to go and
you're like all right I'm just gonna
hack this and you get like an hour in
and you're like ah I don't actually have
the thing that I need yes that's a pain
um all right so you cleaned it you put
it in your reader um like Joel mentioned
in the beginning there's a little um dot
at the corner of a lot of the EMC chips
that uh show you where the number one
pin is and you'll want to align that
with the arrow on your um all socket
emmc reader if you're using that and uh
sort of clamp it down slide it right
into a uh a SD uh card slot either on
your computer ideally your computer has
a uh emmc reader built in at a sort of
internal uh chip level rather than using
like a USB thing but the USB things will
work as well unless you're trying to
access some specific features that only
a emmc reader can access rather than an
SD card reader because they are sort of
cross-compatible but emmc has some
features that SD can't handle I think
right yeah so like the rpmb stuff that
we talked about like that is one of
those specific things where you need an
MMC controller that is in like on your
device in order to interface with
something like that they sell pcie ones
that are that are like proper MMC
controllers but most of the time you're
going to find it needs to be like an
onboard s full size SD reader on your
computer on like a laptop or something
and even then a lot of the times it
won't um if you use like a USB reader
USB like SD readers they are basically
just storage interfaces for MMC so they
have an MMC controller on the you know
in the USB adapter or whatever but when
you plug that in all it's doing is
exposing those storage interfaces so
it's going to be all the storage
partitions but you're not going to have
access to the raw MMC like RPM and any
of those other like special MMC type
things unless you have an onboard MMC
controller so if all you need to do is
read data partitions totally fine if you
need to read rpnb do normally yes
normally speak like 99% of cases you'll
probably be fine but if you want to try
and get at rpmb or any any of that kind
of stuff you're going to need an onboard
MMC controller yeah yeah so now you've
you've got it hooked up you're seeing
the partitions pop in what um what we
did last time is we just used the DD
command in Linux to just pull an a raw
you know device level image of that
device into an image um file and then we
ended up using uh was it seven seven zip
seven zip yeah seven zip to go ahead and
um break that out into the individual
partitions and then you know you'll see
various files created and if you run
file on them you'll see like uh you know
there's a there's an
ext4 yeah or like a fat partition or
whatever you know there's going to be a
bunch of different partitions cuz that's
always what it they have in a bunch of
these iot devices but um you know
identifying all of those various uh
partitions is really fun and and this
kind of pivots into the last section
that I wanted to cover which is like um
Joel what kind of like preventions have
you seen from this because the only one
that kind of comes to my head was like
man we would have been in in trouble if
they um stuck all of the source code or
like the file system for that device
inside of that lux um encrypted
partition that we that we saw for some
of the more sensitive data and then um
and then you you know stored the key for
that lux encrypted partition in in a
secure on cave in at like a hardware
level at the CPU or something like that
um that would have been a royal pain in
the butt to get access to um so I mean
there there's that option I I imagine
that would sort of delay startup quite a
bit because every time you wanted to use
the device you'd have to um decrypt
everything on the partition and then
also copy that into an actual
functioning partition um so that that
might affect the boot speed a little bit
but what what other kind of Hardware
level preventions have you seen that
might you know foil a hacker yeah so
like you mentioned like that kind of
stuff that's going to be like n 99% of
the time is going to stop like a lot of
what you're trying to do you're going to
have to find some other attack scenario
if you want like a shell or something
like that to figure out like what it's
doing you're going to need to like
glitch it or maybe you'll have to read
the MMC while it's running or something
like that right like this is one of
those cases where that might actually be
the
scenario um but yeah an encrypted
partition would stop like pretty much
all the stuff that we were we were doing
there um another thing that you see
commonly and this isn't for storage so
much as it is for like debugging stuff
but there's typically there'll be like a
fuse either within a chip or on the
board um and it's typically called like
a j tag fuse or a uart or a debug fuse
or something and they'll they'll
basically pop the fuse by like putting
enough power to it and then it can never
be reverted so it'll it has a physical
break in the communication between like
your test pins and the JTAG interface on
the chip and you can't get around that
unless you like I don't know do do some
like really crazy like yeah pulling the
chip apart like I I don't have to like
cut into the chip and like get access
which I've seen by the way crazy yeah
that would that would be gnarly that's
interesting though that that that that's
a counter measure that that people might
take you know just kind of putting a
fuse in there and blowing it you know
sever the connection for that sort of
thing that's a good idea yeah I've seen
um there's a couple really interesting
Twitter threads out there I'm trying to
remember who created them but um every
once in a while you'll see like some
crazy Hardware hacker just like put a
video of what they what they're working
on like on Twitter and this one time
there was this guy he was using a razor
blade uh to scratch away the surface of
a chip while it was on the board to
exposed the context underneath and then
he took like you know probably I don't
know speaker speaker wire I I don't even
know like uh you know Co like uh maybe
like a a coil wire or something like
really really fine wire like wire wire
gauge wire and and then like uh I think
he soldered it down so it wouldn't move
and then he soldered the the like tip of
it to to like the contact on the chip
dude it was so crazy I got to I'll find
it we'll put it in the show notes yeah
no definitely find that I want to see
that and I know I watched a um a talk at
Defcon by leoner I think is uh is the
guy that did it uh Hardware hacking guy
um you know just glitching uh I think it
was some SpaceX or stuff or some
whatever their their Wi-Fi thing is
that's everywhere um just absolutely
amazing so there's so much to learn
about in this space which really excites
me as a as a more veteran hacker in the
in the web and and mobile space a little
bit now um you know know having another
realm to dive deep into is really is
really cool so I'm excited to continue
learning about that sort of thing and
being able to do some some glitching and
and some uh some of the stuff that I
haven't T tackled next time around yeah
for sure I mean there's this space is
like what I feel like I've just barely
scratched the surface in terms of
knowledge and understanding and and
what's possible and all that kind of
stuff and I feel like I'm just just like
I'm doing like you know baby's first
Hardware right now still like there's so
much so much I I don't know and there's
so much I haven't explored that that
seems so cool well it's very different
too you know and if you talk to some of
these lower level guys they they don't
have any uh you know experience doing
web stuff and so it's just different
Realms and different sections of places
where people are are focusing and so
it's cool to get some sort of cross
experience it makes you really feel like
a more well-rounded or developed hacker
I think um I did want to add a
disclosure at the end here um this does
not constitute a vulnerability so um
being able to pull the operating system
off of a chip I personally don't believe
uh constitutes a vulnerability um I've
seen some hackers report that I'm not
sure whether they got paid or not um but
you know there's not a really great
countermeasure to it and um and so it's
just kind of a part of Hardware hacking
and more like finding JavaScript files
in in um in web stuff or more like uh
decompiling an APK and grabbing at the
the Java source code you know uh in
Mobile um so definitely definitely don't
go and like once you get your chip and
you pull the data off of it don't go
report it like critical you know source
code disclosure because uh I believe
most of the time that is uh something
that is not going to get accepted by the
program so there's your disclaimer yes
yeah for sure and I I agree I've
actually I've seen people report this
exact thing as as a bug and uh it's
personally it's not something that I
would report either but I do see that
there is a security risk to it uh I
think it I would probably just like it's
a really hard attack scenario to like
justify as like you know a to say like
oh it's a hierar crate or something
that's a really hard thing to justify
depending on what it is depending on
what it is there are certainly Hardware
devices like cell phones that are in
like so many people's hands and Pockets
that that might be a justifiable attack
scenario but I think just in and itself
having a decrypted partition maybe not
enough yeah totally agree yeah all right
man uh that's all I had on the notes for
this episode uh you got anything else or
are we going to wrap it up here nope
that's it I did find those links so we
we'll put them in the show notes be sure
to check out the those links one is from
uh goric and one is from hacking things
both on Twitter I'm gonna go I'm going
to go look those up right now I will say
as we're heading out um so many of you
uh went over to the website after last
episode criticalthinking podcast. and
dropped your email in the newsletter
super appreciate that would love if you
continue to do that um and also please
remember naham Khan uh that that is let
me pull up the dates really quickly I
want to say it's June 15th to 17th um
yeah June it June 15th to 17th the
Saturday is when I'll be speaking at the
1220 slot you won't want to miss out on
that lots of great uh talented bug
bounty hunters there dropping some
amazing presentations so we'll uh we'll
see you there yes so start remember
starts one week from the drop of this
episode so yep be sure to tune in if you
want to hear a little bit more Justin
and some other awesome John Hammond's
going to be there so yeah super super
super awesome security conference go
check it out for sure all right catch
youall next week peace all righty peace
[Music]